kara no kokoro wo terasu mono wa nani?
What brightens up an empty heart?
sakebi tsuzukeru hikari todoku made
I will keep on singing until the light reaches you
falling through the cracks kurayami e ochiteku
Falling through the cracks, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me the story of your life mada michi no tochuu
Tell me the story of your life, We're still on our way
anata o watashi wa zettai akiramenai
I will never give up on you
osaerarenai shoudou nanigenai hibi wa aijyou
Urges I can't suppress, I live for the ordinary days
natsukashii kaze ni furimukeba itsud
When I turn my cheek to a nostalgic wind
emo anata no koe ga suru yo
I always hear your voice
underdog wa wander around
Underdog will Wander around
mawari michi shitemo nigeru yori mashi yo
Even if I take the long way around,
it's better than running away
jibun de jibun o shinjirare nakucha dare wo shinjiru no?
If I can't learn to believe in myself,
then who can I believe in?
hikari ni sono te kazase
Hold up your hand to the light
shining through the clouds kurayami e ochiteku
Shining through the clouds, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me what is on your mind hateshinai yume wo
Tell me what is on your mind,
Chasing the never ending dream
oikake bokura wa zettai akiramenai
We will never give up
kotae no nai jinsei ni kujike sou ni naru kedo
Discouraged by a life without answers, but I...
don’t give it up! keep it up! turn it upside down!
Don't give it up! Keep it up! Turn it upside down!
kokoro wa tsunagatteru yo tatoe tooku hanaretemo
Our hearts will always be connected,
no matter how far apart we may be
tomo ni tomo ni ikiteyukou
Let's share this life together
(ナルト)よっと。
I hear it's true.
That boy, huh?
ほんとらしいわよ。
あの子がね。
Look, isn't that the boy?
He gives me the creeps.
ほら あの子でしょう 気味が悪い。
Hey, don't play with him.
おい あいつとは
遊ぶんじゃないぞ。
You don't know what he'll do.
何されるか わかんねえからな。
Is that right?
そうなの？
ん？
Man, that looks good!
(イルカ)お～ うまそう。
Pops, give me an order of fried rice
and dumplings!
Got it! Coming right up!
おっちゃん チャーハンと
ギョーザもちょうだい！
Dumplings for me!
Gotcha!
(テウチ)へい わっかりやした。
俺 ギョーザ。
はいよ。
ハァ…。
What a weird kid.
He's the kid...
(サスケ)変なやつ。
Did you hear the rumors that
the Fourth died because of him?
あの子だよ。
あいつのせいで 四代目が
死んだって噂 知ってるか？
Oh...
へぇ～。
I'm home...
ただいま。
フンッ！
フゥ… うわ～！
Oww...
イタタ…。
Oh!
ん？ あっ！
Wow!
お～っ！
うわ～っ！
ヒヒッ ハハハハハハハ！
えいっ。
ハフハフ…。
(ヒルゼン)ん？
うわっ！
Wh-Who are you?
Just an old man passing through.
だ… 誰だってばよ？
な～に ただの通りすがりの
じいさんじゃよ。
あ…。
ハッ… ハハハハハ。
(２人)ハハハハハハハ。
Here, gramps, eat this.
よっと… じっちゃん これ食いな。
Oh, thank you.
Oh, this looks so good.
お～ そうかい ありがとな。
いや～
こりゃ 本当に うまそうじゃの。
Well, I caught it.
うん 俺が釣った魚だもん。
So of course,
it's gonna taste good!
Is that so?
うまいに決まってるってばよ。
H-Hot!
ハハッ そうかい。
Look at those stars.
アチッ アチッ…。
見てみろ あの星たちを。
Each one of those stars
is like our world's sun.
あの星の一つひとつが→
わしらの世界の
太陽と同じなんじゃ。
What do you think?
The sheer amount is incredible, eh?
どうだい？ すごい数じゃろ。
The sun? That giant thing that
shines in the sky during the day?
太陽って あの昼間出てる
でっけえやつ？
Yes. This world is boundless.
そうさ
この世界は果てしなく広い。
Yeah? You sure know a lot, gramps!
へぇ～ じっちゃん→
Compared to the vastness of the world,
man's existence is very insignificant.
すげえ物知りだってばよ。
世界の広大さの前ではな→
人間の存在なんちゅうもんは
わずかなもんじゃ。
The things that insignificant humans
fret about are petty indeed.
そんな ちっぽけな人間の
クヨクヨした思いなんぞは→
本当に ちっぽけなもんじゃ。
No kidding. The world is big, huh.
そっか…
そっか 世界は広いんだ。
It goes on and on...
どこまでも どこまでも。
(２人)フフッ… ハハハハハハハハッ！
Do you want some
mushroom soup, gramps?
Are you sure
you can spare me some?
キノコ汁だけど
じっちゃんも食うか？
Sure! You tell great stories, gramps!
わしも もらっていいのかい？
うん！ じっちゃんの話
すげえ おもしろかった。
I see!
Are you sure these mushrooms
are safe?
ハハハッ そうかい。
じゃが このキノコ 大丈夫かいな？
Won't know until we eat ‘em!
食ってみなきゃ
わかんねえってばよ。
そりゃそうだな。
He's right...
Compared to the world, I'm just...
そうさ 俺なんて
この世界と比べたら…。
I'm so small, whatever I do...
ちっぽけな俺が なにしたって…。
But I'm me. That's who I am!
俺は俺 なんだってばよ！
All right, that will do for today.
(ヒザシ)よし 今日は もう
これくらいにしよう。
No, Father...
(ネジ)ハァ ハァ…。
I can still continue!
いえ 父上…。
私は まだまだやれます。
Neji...
You mustn't push yourself too hard.
わ～っ！
ネジ 無理はいかん。
But considering your age,
you've certainly gotten strong.
しかし その歳で… 強くなったな。
Father...
Thank you for sparring with me.
父上 お手合わせ
ありがとうございました。
Oh, Father...
I have heard that your older brother
has a child like me.
ねぇ 父上。
父上の兄さまにも→
私と同じような
子供がいると聞きました。
Yes... A girl, one year younger than you.
ああ
お前より １つ年下の女の子だ。
A girl...
We will be going to a celebration
tomorrow for her third birthday.
女の子。
I wonder what she's like...
明日 ３歳の誕生を祝いに行く。
どんな子かな…。
Father, it's snowing!
あっ！
父上 雪です。
The first snow...
It's going to turn into
a heavy snowfall.
初雪か…。
これは積もるな。
わぁ…。
Look at all the snow!
All right, we're off.
あら… すごい雪。
Dear, please...
(ヒザシ)では いってくる。
Look after Neji.
あなた…。
ネジを… ネジを
よろしくお願いします。
Among the Hyuga,
he is the one with
the most potential.
(ヒザシ)あいつは 一族のなかで→
I shall protect him.
誰よりも
日向の才に愛された者。
HYUGA
私が あいつを守る。
Lady Hinata...
Congratulations
on your third birthday.
ヒナタ様 ３歳の祝いの日
おめでとうございます。
Lady Hinata...
... is a cute child.
ヒナタ様… かわいい子ですね。
Neji...
It is your destiny to protect her,
ネジ…。
and to protect
the Hyuga bloodline.
あの方をお守りして→
日向の血を守るのが
お前のさだめだ。
The Hyuga... bloodline?
日向の… 血？
Father!
あ…。
父上！
(ヒナタ)あぁっ！
Neji is very strong.
When we were young—
(ヒアシ)ネジ君は強いな。
私たちも幼い頃は…。
Neji lives for Lady Hinata's sake.
That is the Hyuga destiny.
ネジは ヒナタ様のために生きる。
それが 日向のさだめ…。
All right, that will do for today.
(ヒナタ)あぁっ！
よし。 今日は そこまでだ。
Neji, you are strong indeed.
Hinata, you have a ways to go.
(ヒアシ)ネジ君は強いね。
ヒナタは まだまだだな。
No, my father's daily lessons are...
I... don't like...
(ネジ)いえ 父上の毎日の稽古が…。
to practice taijutsu.
(ヒナタ)私…
体術の稽古 好きじゃない。
What are you saying?
You are the important successor
of the Hyuga clan.
何を言ってるんですか！
あなたは 日向を継ぐ
大切な方なんですよ。
You must be more positive
and confident.
もっと前向きに自信を持たなきゃ。
I wish I could switch with you,
Big Brother Neji...
You are very strong, after all.
ネジ兄さんに代わってほしい。
No, you must never say
such a thing.
ネジ兄さんは とても強いもん。
I will make you strong!
ダメですよ そんなことを言っては。
When you are in danger,
I will give my life to protect you!
私が あなたを強くします。
危ないときには
命をかけて 守ります。
Brother Neji!
Lady Hinata, it's snowing!
ネジ兄さん…。
(ネジ)あ～！ ヒナタ様 雪です!!
I had a snowball fight with my father
this morning, and I hit him twice!
今朝 私は 父上と雪合戦をして
２発も当てたんですよ。
わぁ～！
LANTERN FOR THE DECEASED
Hizashi!
He's only four...
It's such a pity...
ヒザシ…。
まだ ４歳でしょ？
本当… 不憫ね。
Big Brother Neji...
(ヒナタ)ネジ兄さん…。
LANTERN FOR THE DECEASED
あ！
What are you doing?!
お前
何してるんだってばよ？
What're you doing here?
こんなとこで
どうしたんだ？
If you keep crying,
how am I supposed to find out?
泣いてちゃ
わかんねえってばよ。
I... I...
私… 私…。
Where's your house?
Oh well, come on.
お前 家はどこだ？
Let's go.
仕方ねえな ほら いくぞ。
えっ…。
HYUGA
You live in a big house like this,
お前さぁ…。
and you're crying?
こんなでっかい家があるのに
なんで泣いてるんだ？
I don't have anyone,
but I never cry.
俺なんて 誰もいないけど
泣いたりなんて…。
Never!
泣いたりなんてしないってばよ。
ヒヒッ！
Later!
Hinata!
You are the important heir
to the Main Family!
What do you think you're doing?!
I...
じゃあ！
For your sake, and for the sake
of the Main Family,
many people have made
the ultimate sacrifice.
(ヒアシ)ヒナタ！
It's about time you learned
about these things.
宗家の大事な跡継ぎのお前が
何 勝手なことをしているのだ？
sayonara arigatou
Good bye, thank you
koko kara habatakou
We're flying away from here
karappo no tenohira nigirishimete sa
Our empty hands squeezed tight
namida ja nagasenai tashika na omoi ga atta
Not even tears could wash away these feelings
kagiri aru sekai e fumidasu yo
We're stepping out into a world with limits
ashita moshi bokura ga koko kara kietemo
Even if we're suddenly gone tomorrow
kawari nante hoka ni mo irundesho?
There would be others who could replace us, right?
jishin nante hajime kara motte wa inai kedo
We were never confident to begin with
akiramerarenainda
But we can't seem to give it up
isso
What if...
zenbu o suteraretara
We just abandon everything and call it quits?
motto raku ni naru ka na
Would things be easier?
sonna imeeji hitotsu de
That image alone
matataku ma ni toozakatteyuku mirai
was enough to grab on hold to the future
dakishimeta
that was quickly fading away
sayonara arigatou
Good bye, thank you
muchuu de habatakou
We're flying away with everything we got
kagiri aru sekai no sono naka ni
Into a world with limits
sayonara arigatou sayonara arigatou
Good bye, thank you
kanarazu mata aeru sono basho de
We'll definitely meet again, back there
You must surpass me.
That's impossible!
You're a lot like me.
You have the potential.
私…。
Then I will surpass you!
お前の… 宗家のために→
Sakura, aren't your bangs
getting in the way?
You should just cut them!
何人の人間が
自分を犠牲にしているのか→
If you say things like that,
Sakura will start hating you!
お前も そろそろ→
そういうことも
知らなければならない…。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"SASUKE - SAKURA"